Guide to the Rice University Southwest Conference Faculty Representative records (Jim Castaneda), 1940-2007 UA 152
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Southwest Conference Faculty Representative records (Jim Castaneda)
1940-2007
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 152
36 Linear Feet (36 boxes)
Correspondence, reports, and publications revealing Rice Institute / Rice University's athletics programs and participation in regional athletics conferences.
Biographical / Historical
The Southwest Conference (SWC) was a college athletic conference in the United States that became defunct in May of 1996. It consisted of schools in the states of Arkansas, Oklahoma and Texas. Jim Castaneda, Rice faculty member and golf coach, served as the Faculty Representative for the SWC. In 1997 the official records of the conference from 1914 to 1996 were moved from Dallas to the campus of Texas Tech University, becoming part of the Southwest Collection/Special Collections Library. The archive also contains an extensive assortment of images and memorabilia from each member university. Rice University moved to the Western Athletic Conference when SWC closed, and is now a member of Conference USA. Conference USA, officially abbreviated C-USA, is a college athletic conference whose member institutions are located within the Southern United States. The conference participates in the NCAA's Division I in all sports. C-USA was founded in 1995 by the merger of the Metro Conference and Great Midwest Conference, two Division I conferences that did not sponsor football. The conference immediately started competition in all sports, including football. [Partially excerpted from wikipedia, July 10, 2007. ]
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, reports, and publications revealing Rice Institute / Rice University's athletics programs and participation in regional athletics conferences.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Jim Castaneda, 1998 and 2007-2008.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Sports
Document Types
corrrespondence; memorandums; reports; notes
- Series I: General
  - SWC history (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Survey on scholastic regulation for athletic scholarship (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Prediction of academic success, "1.6 rule" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Relations between SWC and Cotton Bowl Association re: stadium use (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scouting-recruiting (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Eligibility infractions (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Probation (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - C.W. Davis controversy re: conference officiating (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - UH admission to SWC, 1940s-50s, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Texas Tech admission to SWC (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Executive Secretary search (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Publicity Director search (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, general (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Flag (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - NCAA membership (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Annual Reports: Post-Season Basketball Tournament, 1976 Nov. 30, 1976 April 30, 1978 April 30, 1979 April 30, 1981 April 30, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series II: Financial
  - Funds from SWC (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - SWC and NCAA-IRS (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cash Receipts and Disbursements/Southwest Athletic Conference For years ending Nov. 30, 1949 to Nov. 30, 1967 For year ending Nov. 30, 1969 For year ending Nov. 30, 1971 to Nov. 30, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Southwest Athletic Conference Financial Statements April 30, 1986 and 1985 April 30, 1987 and 1986 April 30, 1988 and 1987 April 30, 1989 and 1988 April 30, 1990 and 1989 April 30, 1991 and 1990 April 30, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series III: Committees
  - Athletic committees at SWC schools (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Appeals Committee, 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Compliance Committee (1/2) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Compliance Committee (2/2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Compliance Committee II (1/2) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Compliance Committee II (2/2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Drug Testing Committee, 1988-90 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Southwest Conference Drug Testing Protocols (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Employment Committee (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Financial Aid Committee (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - [Committee of the] Interscholastic League (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Personnel and Budget Committee (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Publicity Committee (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Radio Committee (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Radio contract, SWC-Host (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - [Committee on] Scholarship Limitations (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Withdrawal Rule Committee (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series IV: Athletic organization involvement
  - NCAA (1/2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NCAA (2/2) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - NCAA eligibility reports, 1966-80/81 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - NCAA eligibility reports, 1980/81-87/88 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Case decision, U. GA and U. OK v. NCAA, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - CFA/NCAA TV contracts, cases, etc., 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - CFA meeting minutes, reports, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - CFA meeting minutes, reports,1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - CFA reports, 1982/83-86/87 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - CFA reports, 1987/88-89/90 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - CFA meeting minutes, reports, 1990-94 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Series V: SWC meeting minutes, reports, correspondence, publications
  - 1936-43 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1944-45 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1946-49 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - May 1949 (SWC-SC-SEC) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1950-51 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1952-54 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1956-58 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1959-61 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1962-63 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1964-65 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1968 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1969-70 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1971-72 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1973-74 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1977 (1/2) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1977 (2/2) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1978/79 (1/2) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1978/79 (2/2) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1979 (1/2) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1979 (2/2) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1980 (1/2) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1980 (2/2) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1981 appendices (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1981 Spring meeting (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1981/82 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1981/82 (1/2) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1981/82 (2/2) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1982 (1/2) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1982 (2/2) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1983/84 (1/2) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1983/84 (2/2) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1985/86 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1986/87 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1987 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1988 (1/2) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 1988 (2/2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 1989/90 (1/2) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 1989/90 (2/2) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 1990/91 (1/3) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 1990/91 (2/3) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 1990/91 (3/3) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 1992/93 (1/3) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 1992/93 (2/3) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 1992/93 (3/3) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 1993/94 (1/2) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 1993/94 (2/2) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 1994/95 (1/3) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - 1994/95 (2/3) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - 1994/95 (3/3) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 1995/96 (1/3) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 1995/96 (2/3) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1995/96 (3/3) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Southwest Athletic Conference / SWC Southwest Athletic Conference Constitution and By-Laws 1935 1938 1941 1957 1961 1963 1965 Handbook of the Southwest Athletic Conference 1969 1971-1974 1976-1984 Southwest Conference Personnel Directory, 1983-1984 Southwest Athletic Conference Directory, Constitution and Bylaws 1984-1992 Southwest Conference Handbook, 1992-1996 NCAA Manual: Constitution, Article Three, Bylaws 1981-1983 NCAA Manual, Constitution, Operating bylaws, Administrative bylaws, Administrative organization 1993-1996 NCAA Division I Manual, 1997-2005 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Series VI: NCAA
  - NCAA Council Meeting AEC Cabinet 1992-2000 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - AEC Cabinet Meetings 1997 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - NCAA Initial Eligibility Issues AEC 1997-99 [1/3] (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - NCAA Initial Eligibility Issues AEC 1997-99 [2/3] (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - NCAA Initial Eligibility Issues AEC 1997-99 [3/3] (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - NCAA 1997-2000 [1/2] AEC (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - NCAA 1997-2000 [2/2] AEC (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - AEC Cabinet Meetings 1998 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - NCAA Teleconference August 19, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - AEC Cabinet Meetings 1999 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - NCAA Site Review 1999 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - AEC Cabinet Meetings 2000 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting February 21-23, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting June 20-22, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting September 5-7, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - NCAA Academic Consultants Meeting February 14-15, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting February 20-22, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting June 19-21, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting September 11-13, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 19)
- Series VII: Western Athletic Conference (WAC)
  - WAC 1994-95 [1/2] (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - WAC 1994-95 [2/3] (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - WAC 1994-95 [3/3] (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - WAC 1995-96 [1/2] (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - WAC 1995-96 [2/2] (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - WAC 1996-97 [1/3] (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - WAC 1996-97 [2/3] (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - WAC 1996-97 [3/3] (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - WAC 1997-98 [1/3] (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - WAC 1997-98 [2/3] (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - WAC 1997-98 [3/3] (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - WAC Executive Committee Meeting, May 1, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - WAC Meeting October 27-28, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - WAC Meeting April 30-May 3, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - WAC Meeting October 12-14, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - WAC Meeting April 27-30, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - WAC Council Meeting October 18-20, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - WAC-SAAC 2000-01 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - WAC-SAAC 2000-03 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - WAC Meeting April 26-29, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - WAC Meeting October 17-19, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - WAC-SAAC Meetings 2001-04 [1/2] (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - WAC-SAAC Meetings 2001-04 [2/2] (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - WAC Council Meeting April 26-29, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - WAC Council Meeting October 16-17, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting February 19-21, 2003 [1/2] (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting February 19-21, 2003 [2/2] (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - WAC Meeting April 24-26, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - AEC Cabinet Meeting June 11-13, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - WAC Meeting September 30-October 1, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - WAC Meeting May 2-4, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - WAC Council Meeting September 28-29, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Series VIII: WAC / Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, Quality Enhancement Plan
  - SACS Leadership Team notebook, Oct. 16, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - SACS reaccreditation consulting notebook, Sept. 15-16, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
  - SACS 2004-2006 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - SACS reaccreditation, 2004-2006 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - SACS preliminary findings, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - SACS reaffirmation of accreditation, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Response to off-site review committee findings, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Scholarships and financial aid, 1965-77 (Box 25, Folder 11-12)
  - Grants-in-aid terminated, 1974-1986, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 13-14)
  - Grants-in-aid, 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Eligibility, 1970s-1990s Availability lists / participation reports / varsity letter awards (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - 1970/71 – 1976/77 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 1977/78 – 1982-83 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - 1983/84-1987/88 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Eligibility reports, 1988/89-1992/93 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Participation reports, 1993/94-1995/96 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Participation reports, 1996/97-1997/98 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Participation and eligibility reports, 1998-2002 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Seamless eligibility consultants, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
  - Academic consultants, 2001-2003 See also James Kinsey records Box 9 for SAC correspondence, 2002-2006 (Box 26, Folder 11-15)
- Series IX: Addendum, 1941-2006
  - Correspondence, general, 1969-70, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Alex Guerry, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Open Records Act, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - "Sammy" mascot, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Prayers at athletic events, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Bob Quin award, 1970, 1973-1981, 1983-84, 1986-88, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Awards, general, 1945, 1954, 1969, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Complimentary season tickets, 1948, 1961, 1963, 1965, 1967-70, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Title X, general, 1974-78, 1990s-2002 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Title X, women's athletics, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Women's athletics, 1973-76, 1979-80, 1983-85, 1991-93 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Publicity (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Athletics coaches, staff correspondence, PA forms, 1942-43, 1945, 1966-70 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Scholarships, 1957-60, 1962-66, 1968-69, 1976, 1980-81, 1983, 1985, 1988, 1997-1999 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - "R" Association, 1963-64, 1966, 1969, 1973-77, 1979-85 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Athletics facilities usage requests, concerns, 1945, 1951, 1957-61, 1963-72, 1974, 1985-86 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Use of Rice athletics facilities notebook, 1975-87 (Box 27, Folder 17-18)
  - Board of Governors actions re athletics, 1941, 1943, 1946, 1959-65, 1968-71, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Athletes admissions procedures / requirements, 1970, 1973, 1975, 1981-82 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Athlete graduation rates, 1975-76, 1983, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Legal, 1967, 1998, 2001, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Questionnaires, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Freshman athlete survey, 1962-69, 1971-75 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Game reports, 1988-1991 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Athletics at Rice, statements and reports, 1970s-1990s (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Academics – Athletics, 1975-89 (Box 27, Folder 27-28)
  - Commission on Colleges, 2003 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Compliance Committee, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Quality Enhancement Plan, 2003-2006 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Quality Enhancement Plan meeting materials, April 13, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Quality Enhancement Plan committee, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Quality Enhancement Plan proposal background, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Faculty governance, Spring 2005 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Senate, April 12, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Focus report on standards, 2005-2006 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Squad lists, 1983-84, 1987-89, 1998-99 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Material re action against Karen Fasano, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Amateurism (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Sammy Koskei case, 1978-1982 (Box 28, Folder 13-14)
  - Athletes: Admissions and withdrawals, 1970s (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - College Football Association records, graduation rate surveys and reports, 1980s-2000s (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Students recommended for degrees / Enrollment records (with annotations re. Athletes), 1993-2003 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Students recommended for degrees, 1977-1992 (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Series X: Addendum 2, 1985-2007
  - Athletics Staff Manual (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - C-USA Spring Meeting, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - C-USA Spring Meeting, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - C-USA Summer Rules Workshop, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - C-USA Fall Meeting, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - C-USA Spring Meeting, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - C-USA Student Athlete Advisory Committee, July 9, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - C-USA Fall Meeting. 2006 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Dept. of Athletics (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Division IA Athletic Directors Association (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Athletics Representatives (FARA)l (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Athletics Representatives Meeting, March 4, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Athletics Representatives Meeting, March 3, 2007 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - NCAA: Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Football Ticketholders, c. 1985; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Football Ticketholders, c. 1985; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Game Contracts, 1999-2002; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Game Contracts, 1999-2002; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Game Contracts, Before 1999; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Game Contracts, Before 1999; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Ticketmaster Audits, 1996-1997; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Ticketmaster Audits, 1996-1997; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Baseball and Track, 1993; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Baseball and Track, 1993; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Baseball and Track, 1994; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Baseball and Track, 1994; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Baseball and Track, 1995; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Baseball and Track, 1995; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Baseball and Track, 1996; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Baseball and Track, 1996; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Baseball and Track, 1997; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Baseball and Track, 1997; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Baseball and Track, 1999; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Baseball and Track, 1999; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Baseball, 2000; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Baseball, 2000; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Baseball, 2000; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Baseball, 2001; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Baseball, 2001; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Baseball, 2001; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Baseball, 2002; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Baseball, 2002; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Baseball, 2002; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Baseball, 2002; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Men's Basketball, 1992-1993; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Men's Basketball, 1992-1993; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Men's Basketball, 1993-1994; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Men's Basketball, 1993-1994; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Men's Basketball, 1996-1997; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Men's Basketball, 1996-1997; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Men's Basketball, 1998-1999; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Men's Basketball, 1998-1999; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Men's Basketball, 1999-2000; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Men's Basketball, 1999-2000; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Men's Basketball, 2000-2001; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Men's Basketball, 2000-2001; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Men's Basketball, 2001-2002; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Men's Basketball, 2001-2002; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Men's Basketball, 2002-2003; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Men's Basketball, 2002-2003; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Football, 1992; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Football, 1992; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Football, 1993; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Football, 1993; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Football, 1994; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Football, 1994; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Football, 1995; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Football, 1995; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Football, 1996; Home Games (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Football, 1996; Away Games (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Football, 1997; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Football, 1997; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Football, 1998; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Football, 1998; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Football, 1999; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Football, 1999; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Football, 2000; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Football, 2000; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Football, 2001; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Football, 2001; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Football, 2002; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Football, 2002; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 12)
- Series XI: Addendum 3
  - NCAA-related
    - Academic performance, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Academic progress rate (APR), 2005-2006 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Academic reform, 1990-2007 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Amateurism/agents, 1997-2000 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - ADA, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Appeals, 1973-2007 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Athletics certification, 2003 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Athletics certification, 2007-2009 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - At-risk students, 2008 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Budgets, 1986-1998 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Championship Cabinet, 1989-2007 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Clearinghouse Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Competition Cabinet report, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Consultants, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Conventions, 1984-1995 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Core courses, 1997-1999 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Cureton vs. NCAA, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Dept. of Justice, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Division representatives, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Faculty athletics representative (Box 37, Folder 20-21)
    - Faculty athletics representative meeting, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Faculty representative manager's action planner, 2007-2009 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Freshman eligibility, 2002-2006 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - Graduation rates, 1998-2001 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Initial eligibility, 1998-2001 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Knight Commission, 2001-2007 (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Lagow vs. NCAA, 1983-1985 (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Learning disability/ADA training, 1997-1999 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Legislation, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Lifeskills, 2002-2003 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - 1.6 Rule, 1965-1969 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Postgraduate scholarships, 1999-2000 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Restructuring, 1977-1996 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Retention survey, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Retention survey, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - SAAC basketball issues, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - SAAC campus members (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - SAT/ACT, 1997-2001 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Saturday's Children [book], 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Scholarships, 1975-2005 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Sliding scale, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Steering Cmte. (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Surveys (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Title IX (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Violations (Box 38, Folder 18-19)
    - Waivers, 1997-2000 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Working Group on initial-eligibility trends, 2006 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Conference USA-related
    - Correspondence, notices, newsletters, 2003-2006 (Box 38, Folder 22-23)
    - Student-Athlete Advisory Cmte., 2004-2007 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - SAAC meeting, 2007-05-14-2007-05-17 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - SAAC meeting, 2007-07-07-2007-07-08 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - SAAC meeting, 2007-09-24-2007-09-25 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - SAAC meeting, 2008-05-12-2008-05-15 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - SAAC meeting, 2008-09-30-2008-10-01 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Amateur Athletic Union, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Southwest Athletic Conference, 1956-1985 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Western Athletic Conference-related
    - Correspondence, meetings, newsclips (Box 39, Folder 9-10)
    - Compliance (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Student-Athlete Advisory Cmte., 2002-2003 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Stan Bates Award, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 13)
- Series XII: Addendum 4, 2007
  - Correspondence overworking student athletes (football), 2007 (Box 39, Folder 14)